SUHAIB MUTAWAKEL

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN UX/UI DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

I have a great passion for Software Development and UI/UX design. I spent the past two years working and learning about the field of Autonomous Driving. Alongside that, I enjoy creating beautiful User Interfaces, iOS Apps and providing customers with great User Experience. I have won some awards from my UI designs. I love working as part of a team in which I can grow and be able to contribute to building softwares that can change our future.

PROJECTS/AWARDS

- Reconnect Conference (iOS App) Published in the App Store https://apps.apple.com/app/id1480120486
- FlagSter (iOS App) Hackathon (Third Place Winner) Best Mobile App Category Winne
- Meal Delivery UI (Charming UI Designer Award)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java
- Swift
- C
- Python
- Coding / CSS
- Wordpress / CMS

SOFTWARE

- Photoshop
- After Effects
- Adobe XD
- Premiere
- Illustrator
- TPT, DOORS, MKS

SKILLS

- Communication
- Organization
- Creativity
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Teamplayer

HONORS & LEADERSHIP

- Distinguished Officer Team PTK May 2017
- Outstanding Student Leader Award HFC April 2017.
- · Honors Program Graduate-HFC May 2017
- Phi Theta Kappa Scholarship Recipient- April 2017.
- · Council for World Scholarship Recipient- April 2016.



+ (206) 788 -6392



suhaibmutawakel.com



suhaibtarea@amail.com



aithub.com/suhaiboon

in linkedin.com/in/suhaibmutawakel

EDUCATION

2017 / 2019

EASTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY - Ypsilanti, MI

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE - (Expected Dec 2019)

2015 / 2017

HENRY FORD COLLEGE - DEARBORN, MI

ASSOCIATE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEM

EXPERIENCE

Jan.2018 - Current

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Bosch USA, Plymouth, MI

- Perform software development and requirements engineering according to the V-model.
- · Worked on redesigning the APA system through MATLAB with 5 other teammates.
- · Create design documentation in both text and model-based formats.
- · Perform reviews for requirements, designs, and implementations.
- · Used TPT to generate full coverage testing reports for models and software implementation.

Sep. 2017 - Current

FOUNDER

Qumri Design LLC, Dearborn, MI

- · Worked as part of a team of three to deliver great high-quality Websites and Apps.
- · Worked closely with the team to design beautiful UI Designs and Prototypes.
- · Built Apps that are customizable and user-friendly.
- · Designed all types of flyer, posters, and advertisements.

Aug.2017 - Dec 2017

WEB SUPPORT CO-OP

Henry Ford College, Dearborn, MI

- · Maintained content on HFC websites using the Drupal content management framework
- · Created or extend Drupal websites as needed by maintaining content types and views.
- · Developed and maintain documentation for end users.
- · Provided technical support for content editor and owners as needed.

Jan. 2016 - May 2017

LEADERSHIP AND STUDENTS MENTORSHIP

Henry Ford College, Dearborn, MI

- · Established a warm, genuine and open relationship that encourages learning
- · Provided advice, guidance, and support
- · Supported students in their academic career
- Introduced mentees to academia (the educational structure, its politics and players).